<resources>
    <string name="app_name">30 Days of Tomatoes</string>
    <string name="scaffold_text">30 Days of Tomato Tips</string>
    <string name="day">Day</string>
    <string name="tip1_title">Pick the right place</string>
    <string name="tip1_description">Tomatoes like sun. For optimal development they need min. 8 hours a day.  Other than that you can plant them in the garden, in the greenhouse, on the balcony or in the tunnel. As long as it gets enough sun, sky is the limit :) </string>
    <string name="tip2_title">Pick the right time</string>
    <string name="tip2_description">If you\'re planting outside wait until after last frost date (in my region it\'s 15th May). If you\'re growing your plants inside you can start bit earlier.</string>
    <string name="tip3_title">Ensure healthy soil</string>
    <string name="tip3_description">Tomatoes like fertile, nutrient-rich soil nourishing soil that retains moisture. It would be best if it was sandy and clay. Additionally, feel free to enrich it with compost or manure. PH level should be between 6.0 and 7.0.</string>
    <string name="tip4_title">Choose the right variety </string>
    <string name="tip4_description">Select a tomato variety that suits your climate, available space, and personal preferences (e.g., determinate vs. indeterminate).</string>
    <string name="tip5_title">Consider companion plants</string>
    <string name="tip5_description">You\'ve probably heard that some plants shouldn\'t be growing next to each other, because they attract pests or fight for nutrients with each other. But there is also opposite effect - some plants go very well together. Great companion plants for tomatoes are: onion, carrots, basil, marigold, garlic, bean, lettuce and parsley. </string>
    <string name="tip6_title">Plant deep</string>
    <string name="tip6_description">Bury the tomato plant deep in the soil. This encourages a strong root system.</string>
    <string name="tip7_title">Provide adequate spacing </string>
    <string name="tip7_description">Allow 50 cm of space between each tomato plant for proper air circulation.</string>
    <string name="tip8_title">Stake or cage your plants</string>
    <string name="tip8_description">This supports the growing plants and prevents sprawling, which can lead to disease and pest issues.</string>
    <string name="tip9_title">Mulch around the base</string>
    <string name="tip9_description">Mulch helps regulate soil temperature, conserves moisture, and reduces weeds.</string>
    <string name="tip10_title">Water consistently </string>
    <string name="tip10_description">Tomatoes prefer consistent, even watering. Avoid overhead watering to prevent fungal diseases.</string>
    <string name="tip11_title">Avoid watering the leaves </string>
    <string name="tip11_description">Water at the base of the plant to prevent fungal diseases.</string>
    <string name="tip12_title">Prune suckers </string>
    <string name="tip12_description">Remove the small shoots that develop in the leaf axils to direct energy toward fruit production.</string>
    <string name="tip13_title">Fertilize judiciously</string>
    <string name="tip13_description">Avoid over-fertilizing, which can lead to excess foliage and fewer fruits.</string>
    <string name="tip14_title">Provide support for heavy fruits</string>
    <string name="tip14_description">Use slings or netting to support large or heavy fruit to prevent branches from breaking.</string>
    <string name="tip15_title">Prune leaves near the ground</string>
    <string name="tip15_description">This improves air circulation and reduces the risk of soil-borne diseases.</string>
    <string name="tip16_title"> Monitor soil moisture levels</string>
    <string name="tip16_description">Stick your finger into the soil to check for moisture. Water when the top 3cm is dry.</string>
    <string name="tip17_title">Hand-pollinate if necessary</string>
    <string name="tip17_description">In some cases, particularly in greenhouses or areas with limited insect activity, you may need to hand-pollinate to ensure fruit set.</string>
    <string name="tip18_title">Thin out excess foliage</string>
    <string name="tip18_description">This helps improve air circulation and allows more sunlight to reach the fruits.</string>
    <string name="tip19_title">Be mindful of temperature extremes</string>
    <string name="tip19_description">Tomatoes are sensitive to both high and low temperatures. Provide shade during heatwaves and consider covering plants during unexpected frosts.</string>
    <string name="tip20_title">Monitor for blossom end rot</string>
    <string name="tip20_description"> Ensure consistent watering to prevent this common tomato ailment.</string>
    <string name="tip21_title">Use the right type of fertilizer</string>
    <string name="tip21_description">In the initial phase of tomato growth (vegetative), i.e. from planting to the first flowers, fertilizer should contain similar proportions of nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium, enriched with additional micro-elements, such as magnesium, sulfur and iron.</string>
    <string name="tip22_title">Switch to fertilizer for generative phase</string>
    <string name="tip22_description">In the later (generative) phase, i.e. after the appearance of flowers until the end of fruiting, you should switch to another fertilizer, because that\'s when tomato\'s needs change. Choose one that contains predominant amount of potassium, but it also should have some phosphorus and nitrogen.</string>
    <string name="tip23_title">Monitor for pests and diseases</string>
    <string name="tip23_description">Sadly, there are plenty of dangers waiting for your tomatoes - pests, bacterias, virus and fungal diseases. It\'s crucial to learn to identify them and to act quickly whenever problems emerge.</string>
    <string name="tip24_title">Harvest ripe tomatoes gently</string>
    <string name="tip24_description">Handle tomatoes carefully to avoid bruising or damaging the fruit.</string>
    <string name="tip25_title">Pinch the tops</string>
    <string name="tip25_description">Once the plant reaches its desired height, pinch off the growing tip to encourage fruit production.</string>
    <string name="tip26_title">Harvest unripe tomatoes before frost</string>
    <string name="tip26_description">If frost is imminent, pick green tomatoes and allow them to ripen indoors.</string>
    <string name="tip27_title">Save seeds</string>
    <string name="tip27_description">If you have heirloom varieties or liked some variety very much, consider saving seeds for future plantings. Bear in mind though that hybrid varieties (F1) most likely won\'t produce fruits with the same characteristics</string>
    <string name="tip28_title">Keep records</string>
    <string name="tip28_description">Document your planting dates, varieties, and any issues faced. This information will be valuable for future seasons.</string>
    <string name="tip29_title">Rotate crops</string>
    <string name="tip29_description">Avoid planting tomatoes in the same spot every year to prevent soil-borne diseases.</string>
    <string name="tip30_title">Enjoy gardening</string>
    <string name="tip30_description">Last but not the least, have fun and don\'t stress to much. Homegrown tomatoes taste way better than supermarket ones, so take your time to enjoy them!</string>
</resources>